# Ramphele John makgakga

Pretoria, Gauteng, South Africa



johnmakgakgadev@gmail.com



+27711316212



linkedin.com/in/john-makgakga-087488141

# Summary

Resume, Certificates and projects: https://github.com/johnmakgakgadev/Ramphele-John-Makgakga-CV

Bio: I am certified Data Scientist and experienced Python Developer with a background of computer Science, mathematics and statistics. Agile, self driven and curious to learn more, I have interest using Data, ML and AI for development and data engineering.

# **Experience**



# 属 Data Science Internship

Hamoye.com

Nov 2022 - Present (1 month +)

# **Intermediate Full Stack Software Engineer**

Self-employed

Oct 2021 - Present (1 year 2 months +)

# Trainee Manager - Development and End-User Support

KIT KAT GROUP PTY LTD

Apr 2021 - Sep 2021 (6 months)

ERP development, testing ,production, backups, troubleshooting and end-user support

### Junior Developer - Development and End-User Support

Deviare

Aug 2020 - Mar 2021 (8 months)

Software development, testing and end-user support

# > Intern

Deviare

May 2020 - Jul 2020 (3 months)

Sales, Recruitment and Enterprise Development

### **Education**



## Simplilearn Alumni

DATA SCIENTIST MASTER'S PROGRAM, Data Science and Business Intelligence Aug 2019 - Apr 2020

# **Licenses & Certifications**

- Full stack web development and Al with Python (Django) Udemy
- Control React & Django Full Stack: web app, backend API, mobile apps Udemy
- Build a Backend REST API with Python & Django Advanced Udemy
- Machine Learning Advanced Certification Training Simplilearn 1566935
- kaggle Intermediate Machine Learning Kaggle
- kaggle Advanced SQL Kaggle
- Tableau Desktop 10 Simplilearn 1643114
- Power BI Simplilearn 1402265
- **Delivering Quality Work with Agility** IBM
- Present with Purpose IBM
- Interpersonal Skills IBM
- **Collaborate Effectively** IBM
- Solving Problems with Critical and Creative Thinking IBM
- Data Science with R Simplilearn 1402010
- Data Science with Python Simplilearn 1531501
- MongoDB Developer and Administrator Simplilearn 3347989

- Programming with Python 3.X Simplilearn 1381579
- Getting started with AWS Simplilearn : 3335021
- Getting started with DevOps Simplilearn 3682367
- Odoo: The complete Master Class: Beginner to Professional Udemy
- Data Scientist Master's Program Simplilearn 16466645
- Big Data Hadoop and Spark Developer Simplilearn 1666957

# **Skills**

SQL • Python (Programming Language) • Big Data • Data analyst • Microsoft Office